

INFORMATION

Xiaoya (Shirley) Lyu https://shirleylyu.com 1051726627@qq.com 18761593203

PROFILE

I am a multidisciplinary designer hoping to improve communities through product and education. As a **product designer**, I specialize in lifestyle products, UI/UX, furniture, and spatial experience design. As an **instructional designer**, I am passionate about designing playful and effective learning experiences for informal education.

RECOGNITION

SIT Furniture Design Award

Globa

• Skate | 2023 Winner in Other Chairs

ArtCenter Gallery

Pasadena, CA

- Skate | Furniture | 2022 Fall
- Refugia | Spatial | 2022 Summer
- Sunrise | Speaker | 2021 Fall

LANGUAGE

Chinese: Native

EDUCATION

Teachers College Columbia University | Sep. 2023 - Dec. 2024

New York, NY

Master of Art in Instructional Technology and Media

ArtCenter College of Design | Jan. 2020 - Apr. 2023

Pasadena, CA

Bachelor of Science in Product Design

Minor in Designmatters Social Innovation

WORK EXPERIENCE

NORY, Inc. | Feb. 2024 - Mar. 2024

Part-Time STEM Curriculum Developer | New York, USA

- Developed STEM curriculum through prototyping and lesson planning
- Developed a teacher support system

Teachers College | Sep. 2023 - Dec. 2023

Course Assistant | New York, USA

- Hosted workshops on Figma and UIUX prototyping
- Guided students on applying Figma to mobile learning design

Yang Design | May 2021 - Aug. 2021

Design Internship | Shanghai, China

- Conducted brand and trend research through user interviews
- Developed concept design and CMF
- Showcased design results to clients

PROJECT HIGHLIGHT

Creative Innovation Project | Jan. 2021 - Apr. 2021

Creative Education Design for Kids

- Researched creativity cultivation through play
- Designed a city-based organization and organized a fashion design event among kids to nurture their creativity, communication, critical thinking, and collaboration

SKILLS

Software

Photoshop | Illustrator | Indesign | Keyshot | Figma | Rhino | Solidworks Gravity Sketch | Twinmotion | Unreal Engine | Microsoft Office

Design skills

Product Design | Instructional Design | Spatial Experience Design | UI/UX CMF | Design Research | Prototyping | Manufacturing | Visualization

Frontend Development

HTML | CSS | Javascript | React | Bootstrap